A Guide to the Papers of the Carr and Terrell Families 1735-1894
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Carr and Terrell Families 1735-1894
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
4757, -a, -b, -c, -d, -e, -f
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given as a gift on March 19, 1957, January 1961 and May 17, 1973.
Scope and Content Information
Materials predominantly relate to the Carr and Terrell families of Virginia and Kentucky. Includes the family correspondence of Thomas Jefferson's sister, Martha Jefferson Carr of Albemarle County, Virginia, and related Davis, Minor, and Terrell families; will (1735/38) of Thomas Carr of "Topping Castle," Caroline County, Virginia; and genealogical notes of the Carr,Davis, Minor, Overton, and Waters families.
Also included are nine inscriptions from tombstones at Christ Church, Middlesex Co., Virginia; Peter Carr's Notes on law; and rolls (ca. 1839) for University of Virginia classes in anatomy and surgery, chemistry, law, modern languages, and moral philosophy.
Contents List
- From Dabney Carr [1743-1773], Williamsburg, to his wife Patty Martha Jefferson Carr 1772 Feb 17 (Box 1)
  4757-c
- From Dabney Carr to Martha Carr 1772 Feb 19 (Box 1)
  4757-b
- From Dabney Carr to Martha Carr 1772 Feb 23 (Box 1)
- From M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Thomas Jefferson] 1784 Apr 15 (Box 1)
  4757-d
- From M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Thomas Jefferson] 1785 May 6 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell: Letter to his nieces Patsy and Nancy Minor-- also note of Dabney Carr to his wife, Martha Jefferson Carr 1785 May 9 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Thomas Jefferson] 1786 May 5 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Thomas Jefferson] 1787 Jan 2 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Thomas Jefferson] 1787 Feb 26 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Thomas Jefferson] 1787 Apr 27 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Thomas Jefferson] 1787 Dec 3 (Box 1)
- Rich. Terrell to Mrs. Anne Terrell 1788 Mar 22 (Box 1)
- Th[omas] Jefferson to [Martha Jefferson Carr] 1787 Jul 25 (Box 1)
- 1-page Letter Press Copy, Thomas Jefferson, Paris, to Mrs. Dabney Carr [1787?] (Box 1)
  5670
- Rich. Terrell to his mother, Mrs. Anne Terrell 1788 Mar 22 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Patsy and Nancy Minor 1788 May 14 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to his niece Patty Minor [178-?] (Box 1)
- Samuel Terrell to Col. Garritt Minor 1790 Jul 7 (Box 1)
  4757
- Richard Terrell to Patty Minor 1791 Jun 8 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Patsy Minor 1791 Jul 3 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Patsy Minor 1791 Dec 17 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1792 Dec 7 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1793 Apr 27 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1793 May 31 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1793 Jul 13 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1793 Jul 14 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1794 Nov 26 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to Richard Terrell 1794 May 18 (Box 1)
- Martha Carr to Lucy Terrell 1794 Aug 9 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to Mr. Richard Terrell 1794 Oct. 17 (Box 1)
- Samuel Terrell to Richard Terrell 1794 Nov 10 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Lucy Carr Terrell] 1795 Mar 15 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to [Lucy Carr Terrell] 1795 Aug 25 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1795 Oct 22 (Box 1)
- Samuel Terrell to Richard Terrell 1795 Nov 16 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to Lucy [Carr] Terrell 1796 Mar 28 (Box 1)
- M[artha][Jefferson] Carr to Lucy [Carr] Terrell [17]96 Oct 15 (Box 1)
- Dabney Carr to Richard Terrell 1796 Dec 30 (Box 1)
- Dabney Carr to his sister, Mrs. Terrell [c. 1798] April 26 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1799 Jun 13 (Box 1)
- D[abney] Carr to Lucy [Carr] Terrell 1799 Sep 26 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1799 Sep 28 (Box 1)
- M[artha Jefferson]; C[arr] to Lucy [Carr] Terrell 1800 Nov 24 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1801 Nov 5 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1801 Nov 19 (Box 1)
- Richard Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1801 Dec 2 (Box 1)
- Lucy Terrell to Richard Terrell 1802 Feb 7 (Box 1)
  4757-a
- [Martha Jefferson Carr] to Lucy [Carr] Terrell 1802 May 6 (Box 1)
- Dabney Carr to Lucy Ann Terrell 1802 Dec 8 (Box 1)
- P. Carr to Lucy Terrell 1803 Feb 10 (Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Martha J. Terrell 1805 Sep 22 (Box 1)
- Dabney Carr to his mother, Mrs. Martha J. Carr 1809 Nov 26 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1809 Dec 15 (Box 1)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Carr 1810 Jun 22 (Box 1)
- Maria Willis Wilson to Miss Mary Barbour 1810 Jul 27 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to her sister, Lucy Ann Terrell 1810 Aug 21 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1810 Sep 16 (Box 1)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1811 Feb 3 (Box 1)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1811 Feb 18 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Mrs. Martha Carr 1811 Mar 21 (Box 1)
- Malvina B.T. and D.W. Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1811 Jul 10 (Box 1)
- Dabney C. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1811 Aug 6 (Box 1)
- Dabney Carr to Martha J. Terrell 1811 Nov 23 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1812 Feb 2 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1812 Feb 16 (Box 1)
- Misc. Letter to Sisters [Lucy Ann and Virginia (?) Terrell] 1812 Apr 5 (Box 1)
- Maria W. Wilson to Mary Barbour 1812 Jun 14 (Box 1)
- L.A. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1812 Jul 18 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to her sister Lucy Ann Terrell 1812 Aug 19 (Box 1)
- Jane Cary Carr and E. Carr to Lucy Ann Terrell 1812 Sep 5 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell 1812 Oct 10 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1812 Oct 22 (Box 1)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to her Aunt [Polly?--Mary Carr?] 1913 Feb 5 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1813 Feb 23 (Box 1)
- [P. (Peter?) or D.?] Carr to Lucy Ann Terrell 1813 Mar 12 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1813 Jun 10 (Box 1)
- Martha Jefferson Carr and Martha J. (Terrell) to Lucy Ann Terrell [1813?] Jul 15 (Box 1)
- [?] Terrell to Mrs. Nellie B. Carr 1813 Aug 22 (Box 1)
- Martha J. Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1813 Sep 19 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1813 Sep 19 (Box 1)
- E. Carr to Lucy Ann Terrell 1913 Oct 3 (Box 1)
- Nancy A. Carr to Lucy Ann Terrell 1813 Oct 17 (Box 1)
- V[irginia] Terrell [Mrs. Frank Carr] to Mrs. Nelly Boucher Carr [Samuel Carr's 1st cousin and 1st wife] 1813 Oct 17 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1814 Feb 19 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1814 Mar 6 (Box 1)
- Maria W. Wilson to Lucy Ann Terrell 1814 Apr 1 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1814 May 1 (Box 1)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1814 May 11 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1814 Jul 2 (Box 1)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1814 Jul 19 (Box 1)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1814 Jul 24 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1814 Jul 24 (Box 1)
- Elizabeth (Carr) [Mrs. Dabney Carr Jr.] to Lucy Ann Terrell 1814 Oct 29 (Box 1)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Terrell 1814 Nov 29 (Box 1)
- Misc. Letter [incomplete--1st 4 p. only] to Virginia [Terrell] (Mrs. Frank Carr) 1814 Dec 7 (Box 1)
- D. Carr to niece Lucy Ann Terrell 1815 Jan 7 (Box 2)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1814 Jan 14 (Box 2)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1815 Jan 21 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1815 Feb 3 (Box 2)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1815 Feb 5 (Box 2)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell [1815] Feb 27 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell [ca. 1815] Mar 5 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell 1815 Mar 24 (Box 2)
- Mary J. Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell 1815 Apr 4 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell 1815 Apr 9 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell 1815 Apr 9 (Box 2)
- Dabney Carr to Lucy Ann and Virginia Terrell 1815 Apr 28 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell 1815 May 12 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to her brother, Dabney Carr Terrell 1815 Jun 19 (Box 2)
- B. Meriwether to Mrs. Virginia Carr and Miss Lucy Ann Terrell 1815 Jun 25 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell 1815 Jul 10 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney Terrell 1815 Aug 28 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney Terrell 1815 Sep 6 (Box 2)
- E. Govan to Dabney C. Terrell 1816 Feb 4 (Box 2)
- Dabney C. Terrell to Martha J. Terrell 1816 Mar 1 (?) (Box 2)
- B. Meriwether to Martha and Mary Jane Terrell 1816 Jun 29 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell 1817 May 5 (Box 2)
- Elizabeth Carr to Martha J. Terrell 1817 May 5 (Box 2)
- [Dabney Carr] to Dabney [C. Terrell] 1817 May 30 (Box 2)
- Dabney C. Terrell to Martha J. Terrell 1817 Oct 10 (Box 2)
- D. Carr to Dabney Terrell 1817 Dec 7 (Box 2)
- Mary Anderson to her cousin Martha J. Terrell [ante 1818] Mar 7 (Box 2)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell [ante 1818] Mar 9 (Box 2)
- Letter to Martha J. Terrell from her Aunt 1818 Jan 2 (Box 2)
- Nancy Addison Carr [later: Mrs. David Holmes Conrad] to Martha J[efferson] Terrell [Mrs. Dabney Minor] 1818 Jul 13 (Box 2)
- Albert Gallatin to Dabney C. Terrell 1819 Jun 16 (Box 2)
- Mary Jane Terrell [later: Mrs. John A.G. Davis] to Mrs. Martha J. Minor [Mrs. Dabney Minor] 1820 Dec 22 (Box 2)
- Th[omas] Jefferson to [Dabney Carr Terrell] [18]21 Feb 26 (Box 2)
- Dabney Minor to Dabney [?] 1821 Mar 14 (Box 2)
- D. Minor to Dabney Terrell 1821 Jul 20 (Box 2)
- Dabney Minor to Dabney C. Terrell 1821 Aug 20 (Box 2)
- M.J. Minor to Dabney C. Terrell 1821 Aug 31 (Box 2)
- D. Minor to Dabney Terrell 1821 Sep 8 (Box 2)
- D. Minor to Dabney Terrell 1822 Apr 12 (Box 2)
- M.J. Minor to Dabney C. Terrell 1822 Jun 6 (Box 2)
- Dabney Minor to Dabney C. Terrell 1823 Feb 17 (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney Terrell 1823 May 25 (Box 2)
- Dabney Minor to Dabney Terrell 1823 Oct 14 (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney Terrell 1824 Apr 18 (Box 2)
- Inscriptions copied from tombstones, Christ Church, Middlesex 1824 Jun 17 and 26 (Box 2)
- Misc. Letter [J.R. Cary? Carr?] to My Dear Sister Lavinia 1824 Jun 25 (Box 2)
- Martha (Jefferson) (Terrell) Minor to her brother Dabney Carr Terrell [1825?] Feb 12 (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney Terrell 1825 May 25 (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney Terrell 1825 Jul 18 (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney Terrell 1825 July (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney Terrell 1825 Sep 10 (Box 2)
- [J.A.G. Davis?] to Dabney Terrell 1826 Feb 13 (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to [?] 1826 Feb [14?] (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney C. Terrell 1826 Mar 3 (Box 2)
  4757-f
- Dabney C. Terrell to J.A.G. Davis 1826 Apr 6 (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney Terrell 1826 May 31 (Box 2)
- J.A.G. Davis to Dabney Terrell 1826 Aug 1 (Box 2)
- N.P. Trist to J.A.G. Davis 1827 Sep 27 (Box 2)
- Franklin Almanac w/daily entries by John A.G. Davis 1828 (Box 2)
- Dr. Frank Carr to his cousin, Miss Mary Carr [twin sister of Lucy (Carr) Terrell] 1829 Jan 20 (Box 2)
- Nicklin and Johnson to J.A.G. Davis 1830 Aug 16 (Box 2)
- Dr. Frank Carr to his cousin, Miss Mary Carr n.d. [endorsed 1830 Dec 31] (Box 2)
- Dr. Frank Carr to his cousin, Miss Mary Carr n.d., ca. 1830 Dec. 31 (Box 2)
- D. Oakes to J.A.G. Davis 1831 Sep 5 (Box 2)
- Mrs. Newsum to Mayr Jane (Terrell) Davis (Mrs. John A.G. Davis) 1832 Aug 8 (Box 2)
- Judge Jno. Tayloe Lomax to J.A.G. Davis 1834 Apr 4 (Box 2)
- Capt. Alden Partridge to J.A.G. Davis 1835 Mar 12 (Box 2)
- Wm. Campbell Preston to J.A.G. Davis 1835 Jul 5 (Box 2)
- R.M. Patterson to J.A.G. Davis 1836 Sep 1 (Box 2)
- Misc: U.Va. Class Rolls-- Anatomy and Surger, Chemistry, Law, Modern Languages, Moral Philosophy [ca. 1839] (Box 2)
- Stephen H. Tyng to J.A.G. Davis 1840 Aug 5 (Box 2)
- Prof. J.A.G. Davis' Funeral Sermon by U.Va. Chaplain Wm. S. White 1840 Aug 5 (Box 2)
- E. Taliaferro, letter of sympathy to Miss Lucy Davis [1840?] (Box 2)
- Peter Carr to Miss Lucy Jane Minor [later: Mrs. Robt. N. Trice] 1843 Jul 19 (Box 2)
- Peter Carr to Lucy Minor 1843 Aug 4 (Box 2)
- Peter Carr to Lucy Minor 1843 Aug 21 (Box 2)
- Will of James M. Morris 1844 Mar 13 (Box 2)
- Peter Carr to Lucy Minor 1844 Aug 27 (Box 2)
- From Hazlewood[?] 1848 Aug 20 (Box 2)
- Misc. Letter 1856 Jan 4 (Box 2)
- F.W. Page to Eugene Davis 1868 Dec 24 - 1869 Oct 5, 4 letters (Box 2)
- Reminiscences of the Davis Family 1885 (Box 2)
- [?] to Bishop Satane 1890 Apr 8 (Box 2)
- Robt. Carroll to Eugene Davis 1891 May 4 - 1893 Feb 17, 3-4 letters (Box 2)
- O.B. Supen to Mrs. John Staige Davis 1891 Jul 24 (Box 2)
- O.B. Supen to Eugene Davis 1891 Aug 3 (Box 2)
- Granville Goodloe Eugene Davis 1894 Jan 13 and 1894 Jan 27 (Box 2)
- To Virginia Terrell from her Aunt [?] Jan 10 (Box 2)
- Virginia Carr to Mary Carr Feb 5 (Folder 3)
- [Martha J. Terrell] to her brother, [Dabney Carr Terrell] Feb 7 (Box 3)
- Martha Jefferson Terrell to her sister, Virginia Terrell Feb 7 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell Mar 5 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell Mar 5 (Box 3)
- Virginia Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell Mar 11 (Box 3)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell Mar 18 (Box 3)
- [?] to Martha Carr Apr 7 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell Apr 23 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell April (Box 3)
- Virginia Terrell to her sister [Lucy Ann or Virginia?] May 20 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell Jun 5 (Box 3)
- T.B.C. to Lucy Ann Terrell Jun 5 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to her sister, Virginia Terrell Jun 21 (Box 3)
- [?] to Prof. J.A.G. Davis Jul 5 (Box 3)
- [?] to Virginia Terrell Jul 14 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell Jul 25 (Box 3)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell Jul 26 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell Jul 26 (Box 3)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell Aug 20 (Box 3)
- Virginia Terrell to her Aunt, Miss Mary Carr Aug 26 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Minor to Dabney C. Terrell Aug 26 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell Aug 26 (Box 3)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell Sep 2 (Box 3)
- Virginia Terrell to her sisters, Martha and Lucy Ann Terrell Sep 22 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell Oct 9 (Box 3)
- Virginia Carr to Mary Carr Oct 27 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell Oct 30 (Box 3)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell Nov 1 (Box 3)
- L.A. Terrell to Virginia Terrell Nov 15 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney Terrell Nov 29 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell Dec 6 (Box 3)
- M[artha] Carr to Mary Carr Dec 26 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Dabney C. Terrell Dec 29 (Box 3)
- Martha J. Minor to Dabney C. Terrell Dec 31 (Box 3)
- Dabney Carr to Martha Carr n.d. (Box 3)
- [D. Carr to M. Carr] Fragment n.d. (Box 3)
- M[artha] [Jefferson] Carr to Polly [Jefferson] n.d. (Box 3)
  4757-e
- Dabney C. Terrell to Martha J. Terrell n.d. (Box 3)
- [?] to D.C. Terrell n.d. (Box 3)
- Draft of Letter [Lucy Ann Terrell to ? ] n.d. (Box 3)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell n.d. (Box 3)
- Lucy Ann Terrell to Virginia Terrell n.d. (Box 3)
- [Martha J. Terrell to Lucy and Virginia Terrell] Fragment n.d. (Box 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell n.d. (prior to Christmas) (Folder 3)
- Martha J. Terrell to Virginia Terrell [Incomplete] n.d. (Box 3)
- Nancy [?] to Martha J. Terrell n.d. (Box 3)
- M.J. Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell n.d. (Box 3)
- M.J. Terrell to Lucy Ann Terrell n.d. (Box 3)
- Letter cover addressed to Miss Virginia Terrell n.d. (Box 3)
- Notes on Common Law by P[eter] Carr n.d. (Box 3)
- Genealogical Notes on the Carr and Minor Families n.d. (Box 3)
- Early Genealogy of Minors n.d. (Box 3)
- Overton-Walters Family Tree n.d. (Box 3)
- Political Fragment n.d. (Box 3)